all right hello everyone and welcome to
this session about the cloud migration
my name is Nicola and I'm mostly working
on the UI part of the cloud migration
and together with me I have
Julia hello I'm a developer responsible
for the back end of the cloud migration
tool yes so in this session we have
prepared a lot of content for you so we
are going to start with the some
improvements that we did in the backend
that Yul is going to talk about we will
mostly talk about the performance
optimization stability improvements and
also some really nice improvements that
we got under the hood that is going to
help you to spend less time on the cloud
migration then I'm going to demo to you
some of the improvements that we did to
the UI also the feature that is going to
help you to move the customized fields
to the table
extensions and we are going to end with
the Telemetry new upgrade strategy and
we are going to briefly discuss what are
we planning to add for the future for
the cloud migration
tooling okay thank you
Nicola so before talking about the
recent improvements in the cloud
migration replication engine let's take
a look at the usage of the tool between
the years here there are two charts
showing some very nice growth and we
would like to thank you for using the
tool we can only show the relative
increase here but trust me the ACT ual
numbers are also very impressive so
thank you very
much uh so on the left chart we can see
that the number of uh business Central
tenants migrating their data from on
premise has almost doubled last year
comparing to the previous year and on
the right we see that the amount of data
transferred to the cloud has almost
tripled in 2022 comparing to the year
before and this tendency still continues
this year business Central tenants are
getting more and more data migrated from
on premise we take year 2021 as a base
because back then we removed the hard
limitation on the amount of the UN
premis data that can be replicated to
the cloud and that enabled Cloud
migration for larger
installations and in turn it revealed
some technical limitations and
Performance challenges that we had to
address to better support high volume
Cloud
migration that is on premise setups with
a lot of companies and tables and
containing huge amounts of data and that
was the project that we now
completed so before presenting the
results to you I would like to briefly
describe how the replication engine
works and highlight the parts of the
replication process that have been
improved and then we'll talk about each
of the areas in more
details as you probably know uh we use
Asia data Factory pipelines to copy the
data from a source database to the
destination when a migration run is
triggered the replication pipelines gets
executed and it instructs special
compute Services called integration run
times to access the data in both the
source and the destination
databases The Source can be either an un
Prem SQL server or an Asia SQL database
and the destination is always an Asia
SQL of a business Central
tenant so first of all we made quite a
lot of
improvements uh to the replication
pipelines so now they can support larger
Cloud migrations and also can migrate
wider range of data types during the
execution the replication pipelines use
Asia blob storage as a temporary staging
unfortunately blob storage introduces
its own limitations and and we applied
some optimizations to minimize
them the data replication itself is done
by two distinct processes the large
tables are copied table to table by
dedicated copy activities this process
has been
optimized the smaller tables are going
through the process called B copy during
B copy the stored procedures in the on
Prem SQL database collect buls of data
from many smaller tables serialize and
compress each bulk and then split it
into records in a special
table then only this table is copied to
the cloud where the stored procedures in
the tenant database apply the opposite
data transformation combine the records
together decompress deserialize and push
the data into the corresponding tables
this process can be repeated for many
buls until all data is
replicated and it is very efficient for
copying thousands of tables faster but
at the same time it's very demanding on
the SQL Server compute and input output
capabilities and here we made some
improvements as
well finally it was mentioning that we
use SQL change tracking to identify the
changes made to the UN premis data
between the replication runs and copy
only these incremental changes if it is
possible this part has also been
improved allowing us to recognize more
situations where the Delta syn is
possible and reducing the overall
migration
time most of these improvements affect
migrations from both on premise SQL
silver and Asia SQL but there are some
that make a huge difference specifically
for Asia SQL
sources so let's look at this
improvements in more details and see how
you can benefit from them in your future
migrations looking at the replication
pipelines we changed the way the
replication method data has been passed
between the source and the destination
instead of using the data Factory
activities input and output parameters
we now copy the metadata through a
database table and this allowed us to
bypass the 4
meab um data Factory limitation on the
activities input and output so it has
become possible to replicate an
unlimited number of tables in a single
migration run and we remove the
limitation on the number of companies
being
replicated of course it's important to
remember that business Central supports
not more than 300 companies in single
environment but now all these companies
can be replicated in one single run if
you have a powerful on premise SQL
Server um apart from this we also
removed the calculation on the on
premise database size from the
replication
runs uh this calculation is done once
during the cloud migration setup and not
repeating it during replication can save
between 15 and 45 minutes for large
Source databases and reduce the
probability of
timeouts and finally we expanded the
replication pipelines with the activity
scoping SQL sequences specific for
business Central so now the AL number
sequences data type is supported by
Cloud migration and the numbering can
continue in the BC tenant after
migration instead of being
reset so for table totable copy let's
look at the optimizations here table
totable copy is used for large
tables uh however we reduce the
threshold now the replication engine
picks uh would pick a table for table
totable copy if the data size to be
migrated exceeds
250 megabyte and it used to be 500
megabyte before so this means that more
tables are going through table totable
copy now and the replication status is
updated faster for these
tables uh also tables with a lot of data
tend to have many indexes defined when
the data is copied all these indexes
have to to be updated on every insert
now we disable the indexes in the Target
table before copying its data and
rebuild the indexes after the data is
replicated and our test measurement show
8 to 22% performance benefit for the new
process comparing to the old way of
inserting the data with all indexes
enabled because both the cleanup of the
target table and the data copy are now
happening with no active
indexes uh the replication runs are much
faster and this allowed to prevent the
timeouts for the large tables
replication for the bul copy of the
smaller tables in addition to the
reduced threshold we also reduce the
bulk size so this resulted in higher
numbers of smaller bulks and smaller
bulks are easier for the SQL s to
serialize and compress so the timeouts
occurrences become rare
also they may still happen for the
extremely weak or busy SQL
service in fact this gave a significant
performance benefit on our not very
powerful test servers the whole process
of B copy became 60 to 80% faster the
replication status is also updated more
frequently if the buls are
smaller we also made the diagnostic runs
respect the bulk size before they tried
to process all data in single huge bulk
and that often led to timeouts and out
of memory exceptions now diagnostic runs
utilize the same smaller buls as the
normal replication runs they don't time
out and you can safely use them to
quickly test the future
replication finally optimizations for
the Delta sync of the incremental
changes which are related to our usage
of SQL change
tracking so
if the changes between two change
tracking versions can be reliably
collected the replication engine
performs a fast Delta sync otherwise the
whole table has to be cleaned up and
replicated again so we forced a longer
change track and retention period that
allowed the change tracking versions to
stay valid
longer and that increases the
probability of the fast Delta
sychronization for the repeated
replication
runs and we changed the code to use
change tracking in wider range of the
situations for example Delta sync is now
possible also for the databases that
first enable change tracking
specifically for cloud
migration and now Delta sinks are
happening more often reducing the
overall migration time so all the
improvements mentioned earlier are
applied to both SQL server and Asia SQL
sources however if uh Asia SQL is used a
source it is possible to link the source
and the destination Asia SQL databases
directly without the requirement of the
serialized staging in a asure blob
storage and removing staging allow it to
make the replication
faster so now we don't have to serialize
and deserialize the data and it has
become possible to replicate the fields
of SQL variant type also the errors
caused by The Blob infrastructure are
going away for example trying to copy a
record with large value in a single
field like image sometimes fails in the
staging blop with a message that the
specified road delimit is
incorrect so this won't happen for the
migration from Asia SQL anymore so in
general with all these changes Asia SQL
becomes a more powerful and better
performing alternative to the SQL Server
as a source for cloud migration so if
you have plans for some high volume
migrations you might consider deploying
on premise database to an Asia SQL first
and if you want to migrate SQL variant
fields or Fields with large images then
Asia SQL as a source would be the only
possibility so the process of deploying
an Asia to Asia SQL is it can be quite
fast if you have uh the right service
tier in your as SQL database it is also
well described in the the SQL online
help how fast it can be depends on the
service tier that you have to choose for
your SQL for the for your Asia SQL
database and our recommendation here is
to prioritize its compute and input
output
capabilities of course Asia SQL is not
for free and you would probably have to
balance the cost and the benefit but the
more powerful service tier you get the
faster and smoother your Cloud
migrations will be and with that I pass
it over to Nicola to present the new UI
and other uid driven
improvements thank you Julia so we are
going to proceed with the new
UI and for the new UI we are going to go
straight into the
demo we are going to start in the old UI
and the thing that you can see here is a
rather large Cloud migration that I did
in the old UI beforehand so you you can
see how it is looking like and one of
the things that you can notice here it
is extremely hard to get an overview
which data has been moved and if there
has been any problems with the cloud
migration because you needed to select
the specific records and then to search
for the tables failed if they exist so
for example on this replication run you
can see that the three tables have
failed but you have no idea what is the
current status of this data we have also
seen that many partners were doing
similar mistakes when going live and
these mistakes were costly to fix so in
order to address this we have introduced
a new UI and for the first feature to
demo today I'm going to show you how you
can switch between the old and the new
UI we have decided to support both for
the time being because we believe that
some of you have done the customizations
to the old UI so in case you need to
switch between the uis you can invoke
this setion enable disable the new UI so
if you select it here and you say that
you would like to use the new Cloud
migration
UI the product will take you to the new
Cloud migration
UI the new Cloud migration UI is going
to be shown to you by default each time
when you set up BC Cloud
migration GP Cloud migration and SL is
still using the old
UI the thing that you can see here is
that now we have laid out the data in a
different way so we have a overall
status showing you what is the current
status of the cloud migration like this
and the reason why we did this is
because you have a single Cloud
migration so now the UI is actually
representing the state much better and
you also have a set of steps that you
did to This Cloud
migration so you can see the history as
the migration log which which is below
and we have also split it like this now
you do not need to select a record if
you want to start the upgrade or any
other action we will check the overall
status when performing the
actions another thing that is very
visible is that you have actually
failures and there are six tables that
have failed the replication if you
invoke the drill down
here it is going to be visible which
tables currently have the problem that
you need to address and
fix then if you go back now if we add up
here the system is saying Six Tables but
if we add up there is more failures in
the log so you can see that here is nine
tables that have failed the
replication and the reason why is
because if you select for example this
one
here the thing that you will see is that
the text is not highlighted red and you
will also see that the last replication
status is
successful and if you drill down on this
section here you will be able to see
that there is a later on which has
copied the data that has failed which
means that you do not have the problem
on this table so there is no action that
is required from
you if you would like to analyze what
has happened you can also invoke the
show all replication actions and then we
can show you all of the runs in which
this table was involved and this is the
same data as you have seen before so you
see that there was one run that failed
and then there was one run that was
successful and one record was copied in
toal so with the new UI now you're able
to see which tables have failed the
replication and which tables are
requiring your attention
immediately one of the flows that we
wanted to improve is if a small table
fails in many cases Partners would just
like to migrate the data from this
specific table and unfortunately this
was not possible because we would block
it and then you would not be able to
move this data either through a
customized solution or through a rapid
start so to enable you to be more
efficient we have added this action
which is called unblock the table so if
you invoke it we are going to Mark the
table as pass and we will allow you to
write the data to it so if you invoke
this section here we will say to you
that the table was successfully
unblocked and now you can move the data
through the configuration packages or
the other
means one thing that you should do
before invoking the action is to note
down in which company and which table
failed because we remove it out of the
list so when you invoke the action it is
going to be a bit harder to find which
table has failed so unfortunately we do
not keep the track of the failed tables
then in the new UI you can see the
overall status of the companies so you
can see that I have missed eight
companies to be moved if you are
wondering which companies are
moved and which companies are not here
you can go to the replicated filter and
say
no and here you're going to see which
companies you have not moved from the
on so so we're not going to include it
for the purpose of this demo so just
going to exit
here then another thing that you can use
this new ey for is that you can see the
overall status of all of the tables that
have been moved so if you invoke it
here you will be able to see the status
of all of the tables across the
different
runs so here you can see all of the
tables that have been moved for the
specific
companies you can filter per company and
one of the things I would strongly
recommend you to do is to select per
database tables and to check what is the
status for the per database
tables uh here you can see that the
custom report layout and Report
selections were completely replaced and
you will see that these tables have the
Delta and the reason why they have the
delta is because they are tenant media
tables so tenant media if it was copied
successfully it needs to have more
records than there are in the on Prem
database because we never replace the
data in case the data was replaced or in
case we have copied less records than
there is in the source database please
open a support ticket and we are going
to help you this should not happen but
it is good to verify because
unfortunately that we do not have the
warning system in place
yet and the last item that you can see
here is the upgrade TXS and here we are
not able to get the records because the
table is marked as internal thus we will
just put a small warning the tables that
are internal or marked as obsolete
removed we cannot do anything about them
unfortunately we cannot provide the
account so we just show a warning and
keep an eye on the data that is being
moved
then the next functionality that you can
use this page for is that if you're
wondering what has happened to the
specific type of data we would need to
select all so we can go
back and then if you go to the table
name and here if I would like to know
what has happened to the change log
entry so I can
type
and when I invoke okay and I select the
change look entry table we are going to
tell you that the table is excluded from
the cloud migration because it has
replicate data property set to false we
are also going to show you the message
that it was empty on the onr table so
this page can provide you additional
details what has happened to the
specific table and why the data is not
moved
all right so that was all regarding the
overview of the
data then the next thing that you can
use the new page for is that now we have
a complete Cloud migration status and if
you try to invoke it we are going to do
the sanity check and in this case I
cannot complete the cloud migration
because there are failed tables so I
need to pull the data to make sure that
all of the data is moved and then I can
complete the cloud migration but if I
would like to stop the cloud migration
so I can do something I can use the pose
and abandon actions and I have them here
so I can use post Cloud migration and we
recommend to use this action if you plan
to continue it and the second one is the
abandoned Cloud migration which you can
use if you're planning to delete the
environment and completely abandon the
cloud
migration there is no difference between
these two actions except sending the
Telemetry and telling to us what is the
current status of this environment so if
you regret abandoning the cloud
migration you can simply reconfigure it
again and everything is going to
work I have done this in the log so you
can see it here I have abandoned the
cloud migration because I needed to
reconnect the which is was the wrong
step but I simply did it to show you
that it is possible to enable it again
and pull the DAT needed
and for the last expert feature that we
have we have added an action so you can
sanitize the data so if you go to the
actions and sanitize the tables so if
you forgot to run invoke nav sanitize
table on Prem which we strongly
recommend that you do you can sanitize
it in SAS but you need to select the
company and you need to select the table
that you want to sanitize so it has to
be a specific comp and a specific table
and then when you invoke the sanitized
table we will run the code that should
have been done on Prem by the invoke n
sanitized build action this can affect
the performance of the tenant so we
recommend to run it outside of the
business
hours and again I will repeat please run
this action on Prem to make sure that
the data that you're copying to SAS is
correct okay that was all for the new UI
so moving to the next UI feature is
moving customized fields to the table
extensions on the previous Tech days we
have announced that we are planning to
do this and we have invited you to help
us to test the feature and to provide us
feedback and I would like to use this
opportunity to thank 20 partners that
have participated in this effort and
provided the feedback and tested the
functionality which we have developed we
have shipped it with the version 21
actually because we backported the code
to make it more efficient
to explain the feature if you have not
used it before is if on Prem you have
customized Microsoft on tables so let's
say that to the table customer you have
added three
fields that you want to move to sauce
and you have some fields that you want
to leave
behind so in SAS of course you cannot
have customized fields in Microsoft on
tables so it can only contain Microsoft
on fields all of the data needs to be
moved into table extensions and let's
say that you want to split the data into
two table extensions customer is going
to be copied automatically because it
has replicate data property set to true
so we are going to insert the default
mapping by name and we are going to
search for all of the fields that we can
map by name and type and we are going to
automatically
replicate if we do not do anything the
other fields are going to be left behind
but now you are able to do the these
simple migration table mappings and this
will copy the custom fields to the
Target table if the fields match so if
you specify two table mappings engine
will be able to split the data between
these two table extensions and
automatically map the fields that it can
by name and type one important thing to
note here is that you need to rename the
fields so you will need to prefix them
so they are called the same as in on
Prem and
Inu you can do this in either C because
C allows braking changes but you can
also use SQL scripts because the only
thing that the engine is looking at is
the SQL definition so it is even
possible to rename the fields in
SQL on the keyn note you have seen that
we are planning to introduce name spaces
and the goal of the development team is
to eliminate prefixes and suffixes in
all of the objects including the table
names and table Fields so hopefully this
rename in the future is not going to be
needed to show you this feature in the
action we are going to move to the next
them here in CLE I have two tables one
is customer and the second one is G
entry and as you can see they all have
customized Fields I have already renamed
them through the SQL script so this one
is named pt1 and this one is pt2 and pt3
because I would like to split this
customer table into three table
extensions and it's the same for the GL
entry table I want to do the same so I
want to move two Fields into pt1 and the
other two fields to the
pt2 if I switch to the cloud migration
UI
and and if we go to the extensions
management page
and under the manage extensions
installation status you can see that I
have already uploaded three pts that I'm
going to use as a target for the cloud
migration and this is of course a
necessary step that you need to do
before you can Define the table
mappings now if we go back to the cloud
migration UI here is the action which is
named manage custom tables and if we
invoke it here when it opens you can use
this page to define the table mappings
you could Define it in line by selecting
table extension and then filling out the
other fields however we have seen that
this is aror prom if you make a mistake
when you define the migration table
mappings no data is going to be moved
across and these kind of issues are a
little bit difficult to
troubleshoot to help you to add
migration table mappings in an easier
way but also in a less apron way we have
added a dedicated UI for that and you
can access it through this section which
is called add table mappings so if you
invoke this section
here on this page the only thing that
you actually need to provide is the
name and if you would like to add it so
you are sure that there will be no
mistakes we recommend that you copy the
definition from the SQL including square
brackets and you just paste it into this
name field
here so if I do this the system is
automatically going to pass it and it is
going to set the app ID but this is only
applicable if the table is an Al table
and it is also going to update this
property is the data per company or not
because we customer is the data per
company is going to set it to true then
you need to say that you want a table
extension
here and you need to select which
extensions you want to map so we can
filter down the
list so we want these three table
extensions that I have uploaded so now
here I can see all of the table
extensions that the extension is
containing I could invoke okay however
that would insert one migration table
map in
and then I would need to repeat this
process three times this is not needed
because if you select three
rows then we are going to insert three
migration
mappings the next if we would like to
add the GL table mapping I'm going to
invoke this action
again and back to the SQL management
Studio I'm going to copy the table name
and the thing that you can see here is
that the value is already escaped so it
has the underscore instead of the slash
so I'm going to copy it like this and go
here and paste
it the system is going to pass the
values again and then I just need to
select these
values and when I invoke okay it's going
to insert three additional mappings so
now we have seen how quickly you can
Define six migration table mappings
and split two tables onto the three
table
extensions if you would like to save
this configuration that you done so you
don't need to repeat it again you have
the ability to import and to export this
definition into adjacent file so you can
use it across the environments and
across
replications however if you're a large
provider like an IV and you're going to
have many people using the migration
mappings that you're defining it's
possible to programmatically provide
migration table mappings by subscribing
to on insert default table mappings
event from code unit
4,01 so if you do this through code then
table mappings are going to be inserted
each time when you complete the setup
wizard or if you invoke reset migration
table mappings action on the migration
table mappings page before we move on
there is one important limitation that I
would like to highlight so so we have
seen that some of the partners have
tried to do the following so let's say
that on the customer table they have
added a field to and they already have
the table extension in the on Prem
database and then during the cloud
migration they would like to move this
field from the customer into the table
extension and they would try to do it
like this by specifying a migration
table
mapping so if you do it like this it is
not going to work because the table
extension is now replicated from two
sources and that is simply not supported
by the engine engine is not able to
merge the data coming in from two tables
into a single Target
table if you would like to unblock this
one you can either move the field two to
the table extension on
Prem or you can introduce a new table
extension and then Define the migration
table
mapping most of the partners select the
solution two because it's easier for
them but you also have the solution one
in case you need to use
it moving on to the next topic and
that's
Telemetry uh approximately few weeks ago
we have added support for the Telemetry
and we have added a lot of events to the
partner Telemetry that you can use to
track and analyze what happened to the
replication runs so you you can see the
full list here we have also linked in to
the documentation Topic in the slides so
you can get notified whenever the
replication run is started most
importantly when it completes and if it
completed successfully then companion
tables you can get the Telemetry if it
was started and completed because in
some cases it would throw errors then
you can also get the status on the
upgrade events and in case it failed if
the recovery was completed successfully
and for the completeness sake we are
also tracking when you have disabled the
cloud
migration this part is quite interesting
because you can use it to build the
powerbi dashboards to track the progress
of your Cloud
migrations the example that I'm going to
show to you you can access it by this
link so it was done by our pm and you
can download it so you can use it as a
base to build your own dashboards to
show you what is within this
dashboard so if you zoom in the first
thing is of course navigating to it so
you navigate to the report by selecting
the cloud migration part of it and then
the first tab is going to show you what
is the status across environments so if
you're running the cloud migrations for
multiple environments you can see what
is happening there and you also have the
link to the admin Center and also to the
client so you can quickly access the
environment
itself you can use the data to build
some dashboards with errors and the
other kpis so you can get a quick
overview what is happening and the thing
that I like the best personally is the
fact that you can access the cloud
migration lock so you can see what is
happening within the environments
without actually accessing the client so
if you're running many Cloud migrations
I would invite you to try out our
powerbi and to see if you can get a nice
overview of what is happening across the
envirment um if you want to access the
queries they're also on the BCTC GitHub
so you can use it to build your own
reporting and these are the most
important events that you can use to
receive the email notifications so if
you would like to get email notification
whenever the replication run completes
and when the data operate completes or
fails you can subscribe to these events
on the previous BCT Tech this event
there was a dedicated session on how you
can set up these alerts I would invite
you to watch the recording of that one
if you are interested and we have also
put some documentation articles that are
going to guide you how you can set up
the email notifications based on the
partner
dmetry so that was all for the partner
based Telemetry and now we are moving to
the new upgrade strategy topic few
months ago we made an important
announcement and we have also talked
about it on the directions and we have
published it on Yammer and we are using
this opportunity to repeat it because it
can affect some of you if you would like
to access the announcement you can use
the link on the right to access it on
the official documentation
site in short the change is that we are
stopping the direct upgrate and Cloud
migration Po from version 14 we
currently support the upgrade PA from 14
straight into the lat lest version on
Prem and you can also connect the 14
database and directly Cloud migrated
into SS with version 26 unfortunately we
will need to stop this upgrade but this
is in approximately two years so we are
giving you an early heads up because we
believe that to some of you this ability
is rather
important the reason why we need to do
this is because we need to clean up
obsolet fields and tables
we have not deleted anything from the
table schema actually from version 12
and across 14 versions no table objects
have been
deleted so far we have 7 years of
obsolete removed objects and these
objects are taking around 10% of the
database we need to remove these objects
so we can save in space and the second
reason why we need to do this is because
it is affecting our delocalization
effort
about moving all of the localized
functionality into the extension and
providing you a much better
code we have also received this request
from many of the partners to be able to
finally delete the obsolete removed
objects and to clean them up from the
schema which is something that we as
developers need to do and we all have
around seven years of scheme objects to
delete the second effort which is being
affected by this is that we are looking
into mov the tables between the
extensions so you will be able to push
the table up and down the dependency
chain and both of these changes are
actually quite breaking for both upgrade
and Cloud
migration we have received the request
from the partners to ship the ability to
remove the obsolete objects earlier
before version 26 and we are looking
into
this we have not started the
implementation of this feature yet
however the current thinking is that it
is going to work like this so we have a
table in version 25 that has been marked
with obsolete removed and also field
that is marked with obsolete removed and
we would like to get rid of them in
version
26 the only thing that you would need to
do is to delete the objects from the SE
the second item is that you need to
clean up the upate code because now the
references are going to be broken and
the upgrade is not going to
compile and then the next step is to
simp run the upgrade and the engine
itself is going to check if the table
and the field has been marked with
obsolete removed and it is going to
allow the change then it is going to
drop the definition and remove the field
and the table from the SQL
definition so in short the only thing
that you need to do to remove the table
and the field from schema is to have a
version in which it is obsolete removed
and then in the next version you can
delete it we do not enforce any kind of
schedule to the part part regarding the
breaking changes however we as Microsoft
we need to follow the schedule otherwise
we would be breaking
it to understand better how this new
schedule is going to work this is the
visual representation of the changes
that are going to happen in year and a
half the active version is going to be
25 and here the things are going to be
exactly the same as they are currently
you would still need to go to 14 you can
go from all all of these versions into
version 25 and also all of the on Prem
versions are able to go straight into
SS as we are working on the version 26
we are going to start with deleting the
objects so we will introduce the braking
SQL changes immediately at the beginning
you will be able to see what we have
done through The Insider builds and you
can prepare for the changes that we are
doing and then when the version 26 is
released then the version 25 becomes the
jump build we will be forced to delete
the upgrade code in version 26 which
means that in order to get to 26 you
need to go through
25 so all of these on Prem versions they
will need to upgrade to
25 and then from 25 to 26 as a separate
upgrade step or both versions 25 and 26
will be able to Cloud migrate
directly now if you look further in the
future we are planning to do these
updates every five years so in every
five versions We are planning to
introduce a jumper build when we start
working on the version
30 you will need to operate from version
25 to 30 and all of these versions will
be able to Cloud migrate however when we
introduce the version 31 it's going to
contain breaking SQL
changes and then you will need to go to
30 and and then from 30 to 35 and all of
these versions will be able to Cloud
maret during the session we got one
really interesting question that I would
like to raise here as well one of the
partners has asked us if this picture
means that the on Prem is going to be
supported at least until version 35 and
the reason why I would like to highlight
this question here is to tell you that
this thing that you have just seen is
our current thinking and these are are
the things that we are planning to do
with the current knowledge the reason
why we are sharing it with you is
because we would really like to get your
feedback and to also give you an early
heads up about the things that we are
planning to do so you can adjust and
regarding the topic if the on Prem is
going to be supported until version 35
currently there are no plans of stopping
the on Prem support and if there are any
PLS they are going to be announced in
advance also the second thing is that
it's really hard to make any plans 7
years up in the future so this current
schedule that you have seen it can
change and in case of any changes we are
also going to announce it to you so you
can prepare in
time all right so that was all about the
new OP strategy and the next topic is
plans for the
future for the plans for the future I'm
going to talk about our current road map
and all of the items that you can see
they currently on the backlog and I will
present them probably in the order in
which we will be delivering them to you
the first item is that we want to allow
you to specify the company badge size
when you're replicating the date as you
have seen during Julia's part of the
presentation now you can move almost
unlimited number of companies during
your application so we want to allow you
to be able to specify if you want to
move 30 40 and 50 in case you're limited
by your setup we also also want to
enable you to handle these batches in an
easier way and for this we need to
improve the
UI then the next item is to give you the
ability to include or exclude tables
from the cloud migration currently we in
Microsoft we decide what is being
replicated and what is not for Microsoft
owned tables and if you would like to
override this decision you need to do
workarounds either to delete the content
from the table or to use some customized
solutions to move the data to l XML
ports apis or Json import expert so in
order to enable you to be more efficient
we are thinking about including a new UI
so you can override the decision that we
made so if you would like to move to
change log entries and maybe record
links or any other table you will be
able to do this without the need to
write any code straight in the
product the only requirement will be
that the table is not marked as internal
and then you you will be able to
override the decision that we
did then the next topic is that we want
to improve the handling of all per
database tables so we do not replace the
entire table but to Delta sync it in the
same way as we are Delta syncing tenant
media the next item is that we want to
disable assigning intelligent Cloud
permission sets to all users when you
enable the cloud migration we have
received feedback from many of you that
this is quite dis
disrupting and that you also are not
able to use service to service
authentication because of this Behavior
we are going to ship this functionality
as an expert feature that will be a
small action so you can disable this
default behavior for the beginning we
will not disable it
automatically we also want to add
warnings to the new
UI warnings functionality is one of the
things that is missing so we are going
to warn you if for example if the tenant
media table got completely replaced and
also if you have defined any table
mappings and no data was
moved if we see common patterns in the
mistakes that are happening during the
cloud migrations then we can extend the
Warning Systems with additional
warnings and last item that we want to
add is to add the ability to cancel the
ongoing replication currently you can do
it by disabling the integration runtime
in on the machine which is costing the
integration runtime however this does
not cancel it in all of the cases so we
want to give you a simple action in the
UI so you can cancel the outgoing
replication so this is our current
backlog based on your feedback and our
thinking if you have more items or if
you have any feedback to the things that
I have just presented please reach out
to
us so that would be all for today for
the summary we have following
recommendations so please consider Migra
from from Asia SQL if you have large
databases to migrate or otherwise you
have to have very strong on premise
setup um also for the if you want to
enjoy longer periods of uh Delta sync
then set longer change track and
retention period and consider diagnostic
runs to quickly test your future
replications yes also you have seen from
Julia's part that the cloud migration
link can now support really large
tenants and we have shown you that you
can now move customized Fields with
migration table mapping and we would
highly recommend to setup Telemetry if
you want to be able to troubleshoot the
cloud migrations get notifications
through email or if you want to build a
nice
dashboard we would like to invite you to
join us on ymer so if you have any
feedback to the content that you have
seen today or if you have any questions
you can reach out to jul on me on Yammer
we also have many other partners which
are on this channel that are helping out
so we would strongly recommend that you
join us here thank you very much for
your attention thank
you